hato.be 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy

## What session data will be retained?

Each time a user connects to Hato, we retain the following data for 30 days: the user's source IP address, the Hato IP address used by the user, connection start and stop time and total number of bytes used.

## Why do need to keep session data?

We retain Hato session data for 30 days to use with billing issues, troubleshooting, service offering evaluation, TOS issues, AUP issues, and for handling crimes performed over the service.

## What session data is not collected?

  * Does not log a user's traffic or the content of any communications
  * Does not perform deep packet inspection of your traffic, except where requested by the customer for firewall purposes.
  * Does not perform shallow packet inspection of your traffic, except where requested by the customer for firewall purposes.
  * Does not discriminate against devices, protocols, or applications. Hato is network neutral.
  * Does not throttle your Internet connection.
  * Does not rate limit Internet connection.

## How Hato Responds To Civil Investigations?

Hato will not sell or otherwise release a member's identifying information - minimal information reasonably calculated to identify and no more - or usage information to investigators, attorneys, or agencies unless we are directed to do so by a court of competent jurisdiction in the matter. If there is a hearing in court, the member will be notified so they will have an opportunity to contest the surrender of personal information.

## How Hato Responds To Criminal Investigations?

Hato cooperates fully with law enforcement agencies, yet there must still be a subpoena before Hato provides a member's identifying information - minimal information reasonably calculated to identify and no more. In a criminal investigation Hato is required by the Law to not divulge the fact of the investigation to the member.

## What Hato Collects From website

Hato collects personally identifiable information from end users only through web form submissions, primarily for the purpose of enabling the purchase of services and engaging in support and other conversation. This personally identifiable information is associated with your account and can include information such as your name, email address, phone number, payment information and/or physical address. Hato also collects anonymous information about how visitors use our web site; for example, Hato utilizes web analytics software to track, in aggregate, the number of unique views received by the pages of the web site, the domains from which users originate along with many other analytical data points. Through the use of web analytics software, the Hato website may use "cookies" to assist the tracking of how users engage our website. A cookie is a piece of data that the web server stores on the browser's PC which the web browser will then send back to the web server on any future requests, to facilitate identification of the user should they visit the web site again. While much of the information that we collect from users in this manner is not personally identifiable, it may be associated with personally identifiable information that users voluntarily provide to us through our web site.

## How Hato Uses Information Collected From website

Hato does not use personally identifiable information collected through our Web site to contact users regarding products and services offered by Hato. We do _not_ share a member's personally identifiable information with affiliates, independent contractors, business partners or outside entities for marketing purposes or otherwise. We hold your data private.
